# Alexei Marcilio

### **Analytics Consultant**

🕓 416.476.6409 @ alexei.marcilio@gmail.com 🦠 www.marcilio.com 💡 Toronto, Canada, M4W 3Y8

SUMMARY

An enthusiastic results-driven Analytics Consultant and Business Analyst with over 10 years of experience in Analytics and Customer Relationship Management (CRM). Excellent Leadership skills, plus the technical knowledge to build bridges between management and IT.

**EXPERIENCE** 

## **Analytics Consultant**

Tran Inc. 04/2014 - Ongoing Toronto, Canada

TRAN INC. is a boutique Canadian Market Research and Analytics Company.

- Designed and developed an Azure database and Tableau Analytics Dashboard for pharmaceutical data resulting in 100% user adoption.
- Achieved over 80% accuracy using Logistic Regression and Random Forest machine learning algorithms to predict Salesforce.com opportunity success rates for a major Canadian logistics company.
- Leveraged Salesforce Einstein to identify the top predictive factors for call centre training success for a major Canadian mobile company.
- Discover, document, and analyze key business processes for CRM.
- Effectively scope and implement CRM projects, working with CRM teams, vendors/partners and other major stakeholders on scheduling and resource usage.
- Configure Salesforce.com CRM system to cater for CRM design requirements following best practices and minimum customization.
- Provide training and ongoing support for internal and external CRM customers.
- Design Apex Triggers and Workflow in Salesforce.com to solve known issues.

## Manager of Systems Development

College of Nurses of Ontario 08/2013 - 03/2014 Toronto, Canada

The College of Nurses of Ontario is the governing body for registered nurses in Ontario, Canada.

- Planned, co-ordinated and supervised the design, development and implementation of existing or new College application systems.
- Implemented and Administered Salesforce.com's Work.com which achieved 100% user adoption within 3 months.
- Authored a comprehensive Salesforce.com proposal showing \$8 million in ROI over 4 years.
- Developed a SQL script to reveal bottlenecks in nurse registration process.
- · Bid specialist for RFP response process, including evaluation of requirements and developing proposals.

ACHIEVEMENTS

3 X Certified Salesforce Trailhead Ranger including Certified Salesforce Cloud Consultant.

### Managed the first Siebel 8

Pharma implementation in North America ~ completed in 5 months for \$500K.

Twice an Invited Speaker

to Openworld and once to Dreamforce.

First to incorporate IMS

data into Oracle CRM on Demand Dashboards.

Achieved 4.0/4.0 GPA

in a Postgraduate Analytics Program and in Masters of Science degree.

CERTIFICATIONS

Salesforce Certified Sales Cloud Consultant

Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder

Certified Salesforce.com Administrator

Project Management Professional (PMI)

ITIL Foundation Certificate

Canadian Securities Course (CSC)

EDUCATION

Master of Data Science

Merrimack College

Boston, USA

**Analytics for Business Decision Making** 

George Brown College

Toronto, Canada

BSc.

University of Toronto

Toronto, Canada

# Manager of CRM

Bayer Inc. 10/2007 - 07/2013 Toronto, Canada

Bayer is a Life Science company with a more than 150-year history and core competencies in the areas of health care and agriculture.

- Managed Oracle CRM on Demand Implementation which reduced CRM costs 70%, increased user adoption to 100%, and halved the time it took to deliver analytics data.
- Analyzed doctor segmentation using cluster analysis, physician targeting, NBA (Next best action), sales forecasting, and other technique, using SAS.
- Defined and implemented a CRM strategy through research and expertise in CRM, technology and the Pharma Industry.
- Designed and led Salesforce.com implementation, the only such project in the Bayer world that involved no consulting costs.
- Performed all Salesforce.com administration for the Bayer Pharma sales team involving multiple alignments, and configured the entire system, including multiple custom views and Apex custom classes.
- Developed and delivered a complete Salesforce.com Analytics Solution to the entire sales force.
- Created all ETL, Apex Data Loader scripts, data cleansing using SQL Server and created all schemas, and all dashboards and reports within Salesforce com
- Increased sales by managing, modelling and implementing sales rep territory alignments for multiple sales teams resulting in an increase in sales.

# Project Manager/Business Analyst

Bayer Inc. 09/2003 - 09/2007 Toronto, Canada

- Project Manager and Business Analyst for all Bayer Pharma/Marketing CRM Projects.
- Developed and designed a reporting and analytics dashboard using Crystal Reports which achieved 98% user adoption.
- Led project to model, map and streamline all business processes.
- Communicated issues to all major stakeholders while managing technical expectations.
- Co-Led implementation of multi-divisional Sales & Marketing Oracle data warehouse.
- Analyzed, designed and modelled all business processes.
- Designed and built an Analytics web portal using Active Server Pages and leveraging PL/SQL ETL scripts resulting in a 20% cost reduction.
- Documented functional / business requirements, wrote use cases based on sessions with business and technical stakeholders.
- Delivered enhanced system functionality improving KPIs.
- Automated sample recording through CRM system, a first for Bayer, which streamlined the annual sample audit and achieved compliance avoided penalties by meeting Rx&D Guidelines.

AWARDS

# Microsoft Innovation Solution

Won for Analytics Solution AGFA

P Bayer Gold Cross Award

Salesforce.com Implementation

David H. McCracken
Financial Planning Award
George Brown College

Siebel Customer Recognition

Siebel 8 Implementation

SKILLS

### CRM & Front End Tools

Salesforce.com Siebel

Oracle CRM on Demand

**Excel** 

Tableau

**Power BI** 

### **Databases and Analytics**

SQL PL/SQL T-SQL DBA

SQL Server Oracle Access

SAS Enterprise Miner SAS R

SPSS Python

SKILLS

#### Analytics

**Project Management** 

**Business Analysis** 

Leadership

**Business Process Improvement** 

PUBLICATIONS

# **Bayer's Social Transformation**

Salesforce.com Customer Stories

2013 http://bit.ly/2DP7u3D

# Getting ROI from CRM

Oracle Profit Magazine

2008 http://bit.ly/2Y1OCGn

# **Bayer's Cloud Prescription**

Citeworld

2013 http://bit.ly/2vAxYkP